Tyler Mayes

317-851-7061 57 14th St, Franklin, IN 46131 tylermayes14@gmail.com

Summary

Indiana based web developer, soldier, educator, and experienced leader - multi-talented, versatile young professional with experience in highly-effective conflict resolution and persuasive communication techniques. Hardworking and reliable with excellent attention to detail. Adept at operating in fast-paced environments and maintaining calm in challenging situations. Driven to exceed expectations and maximize satisfaction. Excels at working and building confident, organized, and knowledgeable coworkers, employees, and students.

Skills

- Effective time management
- Personal mentoring
- Leadership
- Punctuality
- Communication skills
- Analytical
- Exceptionally organized
- Charismatic

Experience

04/2019 - Present Perry Meridian High School Indianapolis, IN

Drumline Instructor

- Provide leadership and instruction to grade 8 thru 12 students studying music and playing various percussion instruments.
- Liaise with directors, teachers, and staff to ensure continuity of practice and development in rehearsal.
- Take a creative approach to mentoring individual students.
- Maintain students' progress by evaluating and adjusting strategies.

04/2018 - Present U.S. Army Danville, IN

Infantryman

- Trained in combat, life saving techniques, and physical performance.
- Partake in combat patrols on foot and in vehicles.
- Evaluate terrain and record topographical information.
- Work and train in squads of 10-13 in modern combat scenarios.
- Trained and qualified in firing/assembling carbine rifles and assault weapons.
- Learn about leadership and teamwork through vigorous, high-stress training.

Infantry Team Leader

- Directly responsible for the well being, physical readiness, morale, and discipline of 3-4 soldiers within a 13-man squad.
- Lead team of soldiers through modern combat scenarios.
- Responsible of the individual training and maintenance of their equipment, uniforms, and job knowledge.

05/2018 - 04/2019 Guitar Center Greenwood, IN

Lessons Manager

- Manage Guitar Center lessons department.
- Coordinate scheduling between students/instructors.
- Create advertisements promoting the lessons program.
- Ensure student and instructor success by tracking student progress and discussing teaching techniques with instructors.
- Host/coordinate lessons sponsored events such as open houses, jam nights, and recitals.
- Oversee a team of instructors and accommodate accordingly to their needs/wants.

Drum Sales Associate

- Recommended merchandise based on customer needs.
- Interfaced with customers, determine needs, provide recommendations, and up-sell services.
- Increased purchase totals by recommending additional items/programs such as memberships and store sponsored credit cards.
- Described merchandise and explain product operation to customers.
- Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines, payment policies, and security practices.

05/2018 - 02/2019 Decatur Central High School Indianapolis, IN

Drumline Instructor

- Provided leadership and instruction to grade 8 thru 12 students studying music and playing various percussion instruments.
- Liaised with directors, teachers, and staff to ensure continuity of practice and development in rehearsal.
- Took a creative approach to mentoring individual students.
- Maintained students' progress by evaluating and adjusting strategies.

07/2017 - 05/2018 Journey's Kidz Greenwood, IN

Sales Associate

- Assisted customers with product selection, sales, and returns.
- Maintained visually appealing and effective displays for the entire store.
- Created attractive displays for merchandise to enhance sales.
- Built and maintained effective relationships with peers and upper management.
- Exceeded specific team goals and resolved issues by partnering with staff to share and implement service initiatives.

Certifications and Licenses

Structured Self-Development - Level 1

U.S. Army, Issued 08/2019

"Good Manufacturing Practices" Certified

Westrock, Issued 06/2019

Awards and Decorations

- Army Service Ribbon
- National Defense Ribbon
- "Sales Star" award for exceeding sales goals consistently

Education and Training

Eleven Fifty Academy

09/2019 - Present, JavaScript Development

Franklin Central High School

08/2014 - 05/2018, High School Diploma

Fort Benning, GA

08/2018 - 12/2018, Basic Combat Training, Basic Infantry Training

Activities and Honors

- Member of high school marching band and indoor percussion.
- Served as co-section leader of the drumline for 3 years.
- Competed in world class at a state and national level for indoor percussion.